Finding Aid for the Louis Jolyon West Papers LSC.0590
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 5. Professional Associations., 1953-1989.
  - 5.7 Miscellaneous Professional Activities., 1953-1995.
    - National Depressive and Manic-Depressive Association., 1989 November 8-1994 November 18, 1997 July 27-29. (Box 43, Folder 4)
      Folder contains materials related to the National Depressive and Manic-Depressive Association (NDMDA or National DMDA)
    - The Pavlovian Society., 1989 February-1994 June. (Box 43, Folder 5)
      Folder contains materials related to The Pavlovian Society.
    - Phoenix House., 1986 January-1988 November, 1992 May-1994 April. (Box 43, Folder 6)
      Folder contains materials related to Phoenix House
    - Polar Research Board (Folder 1 of 2)., 1983 August-1985 August, 1988 September-1989 August. (Box 43, Folder 7)
      Folder contains materials related to the Polar Research Board, Part of the National Research Council
    - Polar Research Board (Folder 2 of 2)., 1983 August-1985 August, 1988 September-1989 August. (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - U.S. Senate Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations., 1995 October-November. (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - 5.8 National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)., 1967-1987.
    - National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)--1968 National Advisory Mental Health Council., 1967 November 20-1969 March 18. (Box 33, Folder 9)
      Meeting Dates: June 10-12, September 19-20, November 25-27, 1968. Folder includes pamphlet announcing publication of "Academic Psychiatry in Oklahoma: a history," by LJW, September 1968.
    - National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)--1969 Workshop on Psychotomimetics., 1969 January 9- February 10. (Box 33, Folder 10)
      Workshop Dates: January 25-26, 1969
    - National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)--1969 National Advisory Mental Health Council., 1968 November 12- 1969 June 18. (Box 34, Folder 1)
      Meeting Dates: June 16-18, 1969
    - National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)--1972 Ad Hoc Review Committee for Drug Abuse Training., 1972 January 26-September 12. (Box 34, Folder 2)
      Meeting Dates: April 3-4, September 11-12, 1972
    - National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)--1987 Workshop on "Self-Regulation and Risk Taking Behavior"., 1987 April 29-August 21. (Box 34, Folder 3)
      Workshop dates June 7-9, 1987
- 6. Academic Career., 1950-1996.
  The Academic Career series contains six subseries: UCLA--Committees, activities, teaching, and grant applications; UCLA--Promotions, sabbaticals, and retirement; UCLA Center for Preventative Psychiatry; UCLA Center for the Study and Reduction of Violence; UCLA Neuropsychiatric Institute; and the University of Oklahoma. Each series relates to aspects of his work or a center that he headed.
  - 6.1 UCLA--Committees, activities, teaching, and grant applications., 1959-1996.
    - UCLA--Academic Senate (Folder 1 of 8)., 1969 October 13-December 15. (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - UCLA--Academic Senate (Folder 2 of 8)., 1969 August 13-1970 June 11. (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - UCLA--Academic Senate (Folder 3 of 8)., 1970 May 25-1971 October 11. (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - UCLA--Academic Senate (Folder 4 of 8)., 1969 November 11-1972 March 28. (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - UCLA--Academic Senate (Folder 5 of 8)., 1970 July 24-1971 April 21. (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - UCLA--Academic Senate (Folder 6 of 8)., 1972 March 8-December 5. (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - UCLA--Academic Senate (Folder 7 of 8)., 1996 October 25-November 6. (Box 47, Folder 4)
      Contains 1996 Investigator's Manual on Research with Human Subjects (Part 1)
    - UCLA--Academic Senate (Folder 8 of 8)., 1996 October. (Box 47, Folder 5)
      Contains 1996 Investigator's Manual on Research with Human Subjects (Part 2)
    - UCLA--Faculty prospects (Folder 1 of 2)., 1965-1970. (Box 47, Folder 6)
      Folder contains CVs of prospective faculty.
    - UCLA--Faculty prospects (Folder 2 of 2)., 1966-1969. (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - UCLA--Correspondence regarding new appointment (Folder 1 of 2)., 1968 July, 1969 January 2-June 13. (Box 48, Folder 1)
      Contains correspondence about faculty assignments and reassignments.
    - UCLA--Correspondence regarding new appointment (Folder 2 of 2)., 1967 June 30-November 14, 1969 January 20-April 16. (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - UCLA Department of Psychiatry--1969-1971 Graduate Education Committee Meeting minutes., 1969 September 19-1972 June 30. (Box 48, Folder 3)
      Folder contains meeting minutes and memos, and a photograph of the 1970-1971 residents.
    - University Extension., 1970 December 22-1972. (Box 48, Folder 4)
      "The Human Agenda" April 26, 1971; "Hypnosis-Theory and Practice," February 26-28, 1971; "Issues and Dilemmas in Mental Retardation," October 21, 1971; "Cultural Aspects of Alcoholism and Prevention," November 28, 1972; "What is the future of psychiatry," October 30, 1971 (Cancelled), "Legal Homicide-A Critique of Capital Punishment," October 23, 1971.
    - Harbor-UCLA Medical Center., 1969 October 22, 1989 June 6-December 5. (Box 48, Folder 5)
      Pediatric Grand Rounds, November 9, 1989--LJW presented "Cults."
    - UCLA Chapter of Sigma Xi, The Scientific Research Society., 1986 May 9-1987 April 1. (Box 48, Folder 6)
      LJW member, speaker at Dinner Meeting, March 26, 1987 "Violence in America-An Epidemic."
    - UCLA--Speaking engagements., 1969 August, 1971 October 4-1972 September 29, 1974 March 20-June 20, 1987 Feb 6, 1988 December 16-1989 May 22. (Box 48, Folder 7)
      UCLA Administrators and Supervisors Association, October 19, 1971; UCLA Alumni College, October 9-11, 1972; UCLA Medicine and Society Forum, June 20, 1974;Pacific Palisades Optimists Club (for the UCLA Speakers Bureau), "Terrorism," February 17, 1987; UCLA Hippocratic Oath Ceremony, June 9, 1989; UCLA/San Fernando Valley Psychiatry Training Program, Veterans Administration Hospital, "Alcoholism," April 28, 1989; UCLA Staff and Faculty Service Center, "Undermining Mind Control," May 25, 1989.
    - UCLA--Meetings., 1971 March 31-April 1, 1972 April 26-June 7,1988 July 29, 1989 April 12- October 16. (Box 48, Folder 8)
      UCLA Department of Psychiatry Adult Division Meeting, June 18-20, 1971 and June 9-11, 1972;UCLA Department of Psychiatry Annual Faculty Dinner, October 13, 1971;UCLA Medical Center Medical Staff Annual Meeting, May 25, 1989;UCLA Foundation Board of Trustees, November 14, 1989.
    - Medicare Time Study., 1993 July 12- 1994 June 22. (Box 48, Folder 9)
      Contains daily schedule for almost one year.
    - UCLA--Newsletters and correspondence., 1969-1971, 1982-1983, 1994 August 5. (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - UCLA Department of Psychiatry--Academic Advisory Committee., 1969 April 22-December 23. (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - UCLA Hospital and Clinics--Executive Committee Meetings (Folder 1 of 3)., 1970 May 20-December 11. (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - UCLA Hospital and Clinics--Executive Committee Meetings (Folder 2 of 3)., 1970 February 17-May 18. (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - UCLA Hospital and Clinics--Executive Committee Meetings (Folder 3 of 3)., 1971 February 9-June 21. (Box 49, Folder 5)
      Folder contains 1971 meetings' agenda and minutes.
    - UCLA School of Medicine-Faculty Council meetings and correspondence (Folder 1 of 3)., 1969 November 7-1970 November 2. (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - UCLA School of Medicine--Faculty Council meetings and correspondence (Folder 2 of 3)., 1971 January 4-July 12. (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - UCLA School of Medicine-- Faculty Council meeting minutes (Folder 3 of 3)., 1971 June 30-1972 June 17. (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - UCLA School of Medicine--1987, 1989 Faculty Council retreats., 1986 September 12-1987 May 19, 1989 May 5-July 5. (Box 50, Folder 1)
      Retreat dates April 9-11, 1987 and May 18-20, 1989.
    - Angela Davis., 1970 April 27- 1971 October 7-14. (Box 50, Folder 2)
      Materials related to the non-renewal of Angela Davis's academic appointment at UCLA and Chancellor Young's decision to reappoint her.
    - Course materials--"Interpersonal Violence in America Today"., 1978 April 4-June 6. (Box 50, Folder 3)
      Freshman/Sophomore Professional School Seminar, Spring 1978. Folder contains syllabus and weekly readings.
    - Course materials--"Violence in America"., 1994-1995. (Box 50, Folder 4)
      Seminar LJW taught in Spring 1995 and possibly in 1990, part of the Professional Schools Seminar Program (PSSP).
    - Grant Information and Correspondence--Medical Television., 1959 March 16-1968 August 16. (Box 50, Folder 5)
      UCLA
    - Grants--UCLA Regional Medical Programs General Information., 1967 July 12. (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Grant Information and Correspondence--General Practitioners (Folder 1 of 2)., 1965 February 19-1968 December 2. (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Grant Information and Correspondence--General Practitioners (Folder 2 of 2)., 1959 April 10-1966 March 4. (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - UCLA Department of Psychiatry and Biobehavioral Sciences Faculty Congress., 1988 December 16-17. (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - UCLA Department of Psychiatry and Biobehavioral Sciences Faculty Congress-- Expenses., 1989 January. (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - 6.2 UCLA--Promotions, sabbaticals and retirement., 1962-1993.
    - Promotion., 1992 April 30- 1993 October 6. (Box 46, Folder 1)
      Correspondence related to 1992 promotion to Professor, Above-Scale while faculty at UCLA.
    - Outside professional activities annual report., 1987 July 1- 1993 June 30. (Box 46, Folder 2)
      Annual report of outside professional activities while faculty at UCLA.
    - UCLA appointment information., 1969 July 1- 1986 June, 1994 March 8-April 19. (Box 46, Folder 3)
      Correspondence related to UCLA faculty appointments and decision not to retire in 1994.
    - Promotion., 1977- 1983 July 13. (Box 46, Folder 4)
      Correspondence related to 1991 promotion while faculty at UCLA.
    - Promotion., 1976 November 4- 1977 July 1, 1992 March. (Box 46, Folder 5)
      Correspondence related to 1978 promotion while faculty at UCLA.
    - Promotion., 1972. (Box 46, Folder 6)
      Correspondence related to 1972 promotion while faculty at UCLA.
    - Reappointment material., 1982 June 14- 1991 February 7. (Box 46, Folder 7)
      Correspondence related to reappointment as Chair at UCLA.
    - Honors and achievements., 1989 August 1- 1992 August 7. (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Curriculum Vitae., 1962 October 9- 1971 October 22. (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - UCLA Sabbatical leaves., 1975 June 12- 1993 June 14. (Box 46, Folder 10)
      Correspondence related to sabbatical leaves while faculty at UCLA.
  - 6.3 UCLA Center for Preventive Psychiatry., 1984-1994.
    - Cultic Studies Research Center and Database Repository., 1994 February 25. (Box 44, Folder 3)
      Proposal for center
    - "Prevention and the Field of Mental Health"., 1989. (Box 44, Folder 4)
      Article by Anne West, H. Pardes, and M. Silverman in the American Review of Public Health, 1989.
    - Fundraising foundations., 1984 October 7- 1987 February 16. (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Executive committee., 1986 October 23- 1988 November 21. (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence regarding expenditures., 1988 April 27- 1989 July 18. (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - UCLA National Conference on Preventative Psychiatry 1987-1988., 1986 November 25-1988 August 23. (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Goldston files--Donations listings., 1987 October- 1988 May 27. (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Donations--Pynoos., 1987 November 17-1988 May 3. (Box 45, Folder 1)
      Donors received a Louise Nevelson collage. Correspondence between donors, Dr. Goldston, and Morris S. Pynoos.
    - Council for Preventive Psychiatry., 1987 May 30-1989 August 1. (Box 45, Folder 2)
      The Council is the support group for the UCLA Preventive Psychiatry Center. Folder contains papers pertaining to the center's relationship with the Council for Preventive Psychiatry and an event with Dr. Simon Wile
    - Public Relations., 1987 April 24- 1988 August 16. (Box 45, Folder 3)
      Contains correspondence pertaining to Council and Center and events
    - Council events., 1989 February 2, undated. (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence regarding the Preventive Psychiatry Center., 1987 March 9- 1990 June 21. (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - 6.4 UCLA Center for the Study and Reduction of Violence (CSRV)., 1950-1976.
    Subseries includes materials related to the Center for the Reduction of Life-Threatening Behavior, which was essentially what the CSRV was to become.
    - Meetings., 1973 April 4-October 29. (Box 51, Folder 1)
      Folder contains materials related to 1)LJW's attendance at the California State Senate Health and Welfare Committee Special Hearing, April 11, 1973, 2)A panel discussion of the CSRV at the UCLA School of Law, November 5, 1973, 3)A conference in Sacramento regarding the CSRV, June 11, 1973.
    - Organization of the CSRV., 1973. (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - "The psychosurgery flap" (Folder 1 of 2)., 1973 February 14-1975 April 20. (Box 51, Folder 3)
      Folder contains original pamphlets of opponents of CSRV
    - "The psychosurgery flap" (Folder 2 of 2)., 1973 February-1974 April. (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Public Advisory Committee., 1973-1974. (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Writings, newspaper clippings, and pamphlets (Folder 1 of 3)., 1973 March 20-1974 April 8. (Box 51, Folder 6)
      CSRV
    - Writings, newspaper clippings, and pamphlets (Folder 2 of 3)., 1973 April 11-1976 January 14. (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Writings, newspaper clippings, and pamphlets (Folder 3 of 3)., 1973 February-1974 July, 1977 August-December. (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Administration of the CSRV., 1973. (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Science Software Systems--Violence film., 1972-1973. (Box 51, Folder 10)
      Materials related to a 20 minute film to be made for the CSRV by Science Software Systems, R. Boolootian, President.
    - Human Use Committee., 1972-1973. (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Budget information., 1973. (Box 52, Folder 1)
      Folder includes information and budgeting for proposed research on violence and the CSRV.
    - NIKE Missile Flap & the Daily Bruin., 1973-1975. (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - National Caucus of Labor Committees., 1974. (Box 52, Folder 3)
      Includes an "Indictment for Crimes Against Humanity" against LJW.
    - "The Case for Research on Violence"., 1974 February 25-March 18. (Box 52, Folder 4)
      Published in the Daily Bruin on February 25, 1974.
    - The Hastings Center, Case Study Workshop (Folder 1 of 4)., 1972 September, 1973 January, 1978 January 25-February 3. (Box 52, Folder 5)
      Includes "Anatomy of a Violence Center," a timeline of events surrounding CSRV
    - The Hastings Center, Case Study Workshop (Folder 2 of 4)., 1973 February 14-August 1. (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - The Hastings Center, Case Study Workshop (Folder 3 of 4)., 1973 April 24-1974 January 10. (Box 52, Folder 7)
      Contains correspondence with Hon. Willie Brown of San Francisco
    - The Hastings Center, Case Study Workshop (Folder 4 of 4)., 1973 July 23-1974 March 19. (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - "Project on Life-Threatening Behavior"., 1974. (Box 52, Folder 9)
      Paper likely written by LJW. Contains information about campus referendum on the opposition of the CSRV.
    - Battered Child Syndrome., 1968, 1971-1973. (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Statements regarding the CSRV., 1973-1974. (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Advisory Council., 1973-1974. (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Rosters., 1974. (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Media Medical Writers meeting., 1973. (Box 53, Folder 1)
      Meeting held in California Room of Faculty Center on May 24, 1973.
    - Budget., 1973-1975. (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Curriculum vitae of principle investigators (Folder 1 of 2)., 1972-1973. (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Curriculum vitae of principle investigators (Folder 2 of 2)., 1972-1973. (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Meeting notes., 1973-1974. (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Executive Committee., 1973. (Box 53, Folder 6)
      Folder contains CSRV Executive Committee meeting minutes, Chairman: LJW.
    - Center for the Study of Violent Behavior: Report of Program and Budget--Phase One., 1973 February 20. (Box 53, Folder 7)
      Precursor to CSRV. Phase one: to June 30, 1973.
    - Center for the Study of Violent Behavior: Proposed Program and Budget--Phase One and Phase Two., 1973 March 1. (Box 53, Folder 8)
      Precursor to the CSRV. Proposal submitted by LJW to J.M. Stubblebine, Director of Health, Office of Health Planning, State of California. Phase One: January 1-June 30, 1973 and Phase Two: July 1, 1973-June 30, 1974.
    - Program Description., 1973 April-September. (Box 53, Folder 9)
      Folder contains materials related to CSRV timeline, facilities, budget, funding, research review procedure.
    - Plan of Program--Volume One: Pr?cis., 1973 June 15. (Box 53, Folder 10)
      Plan for CSRV July 1, 1973 -June 30, 1974
    - Plan of Program--Volume One: Pr?cis--revisions., 1973. (Box 53, Folder 11)
      Folder includes drafts and revisions of the CSRV Plan of Program: July 1, 1973-June 30, 1974--Volume One: Pr?cis. See Box 58 Folders 5-6 for related materials.
    - Plan of Program--Volume One: Pr?cis--revised., 1973 June 25, 1974 February 1. (Box 53, Folder 12)
      Plan of Program: July 1, 1973-June 30, 1974. Revised version. Includes Affidavit dated February 1, 1974 that highlights plans regarding surgery, prisoners, and the Human Subjects Review Committee.
    - Plan of Program, Volume Two (Folder 1 of 2)., undated. (Box 54, Folder 1)
      Includes curriculum vitae of Principal Investigators and Selected References
    - Plan of Program, Volume Two (Folder 2 of 2)., undated. (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - The Project on Life-Threatening Behavior--Volume One and Two., 1974 January 1. (Box 54, Folder 3)
      Volume I: Pr?cis and Volume II: Elements. From the Laboratory for the Study of Life-Threatening Behavior at the NPI.
    - Violence research conducted at UCLA (Folder 1 of 2)., ca. 1973. (Box 54, Folder 4)
      Folder includes a list of projects and papers about violence by researchers at UCLA including "Child Trauma Intervention," "Anterior Pituitary Hormone Secretion Patterns in XXY Males," "Agnostic Behavior as a Consequence of Social System Disequilibrium," "The Violent Adolescent in the Family," "Working with Hyperkinetic Children," "Hormonal, Psychological, and Familial Aspects of Passivity and Aggressivity in Boys," "Experimental Animal Violence: Relations with Drug Dependence," "A Study of Life-Threatening Behavior During the Menstrual Cycle," "Effects of Drugs on the Psychophysiological Correlates of Emotional States of Anger and Frustration," "Victims of Life-Threatening Behavior," "Mescaline and Aggression in Rats," "Proposal: To Study and Ameliorate Conditions of Life-Threatening Behavior/Crime in the Schools: The Role of the Administrator," "Taxonomic and Epidemiological Study,"
    - Violence research conducted at UCLA (Folder 2 of 2)., ca. 1973. (Box 54, Folder 5)
      Folder contains papers about violence by researchers at UCLA including "Drugs and Violence: Comprehensive Review of Drug-Violence Literature," "The Influence of Combat on the Appearance of Life-Threatening Behavior in the Psychiatric Problems of Veterans," "Crisis Intervention for Life-Threatening Behavior," "Study of the Verbal Control of Behavior and Cerebral Dominance in Hyperkinetic Children."
    - Violence research (Folder 1 of 7)., 1973, undated. (Box 54, Folder 6)
      Folder includes papers by other authors regarding violence.
    - Violence research (Folder 2 of 7)., 1973 August 20-September 25. (Box 54, Folder 7)
      Report on the "Research Aspects of the Neurological Bases of Aggressive (Violent) Behavior," by the National Institute of Neurological Diseases and Stroke (NINDS) of the NIH, CSRV.
    - Violence research (Folder 3 of 7)., 1971-1973. (Box 54, Folder 8)
      Folder contains "Violence Prevention: A Health Problem," by B. Justice, Ph.D.
    - Violence research (Folder 4 of 7)., ca. 1973. (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Violence research (Folder 5 of 7)., undated. (Box 55, Folder 2)
      "Not included in August 1973 Revision." Includes paper "Violence and Hyperkinetic Children" with editing.
    - Violence research (Folder 6 of 7)., 1973, undated. (Box 55, Folder 3)
      Folder includes research and proposed research on violence and children and violence and drugs. See Box 53 Folder 11 for related materials.
    - Violence research (Folder 7 of 7)., ca. 1973. (Box 55, Folder 4)
      Folder includes research and proposed research on violence and children. See Box 53 Folder 11 for related materials.
    - Proposed research (Folder 1 of 4)., 1972-1973. (Box 55, Folder 5)
      Folder includes proposal for the Center for the Reduction of Life Threatening Behavior--California Department of Mental Hygiene, and other information and proposals related to research on violence and the CSRV. Includes CV's of Litman, McCreary, Oakes, Paulson, Rickles, Seeley, West, and Westman.
    - Proposed research (Folder 2 of 4)., 1972-1973. (Box 55, Folder 6)
      Folder includes information and proposals related to research on violence and the CSRV.
    - Proposed research (Folder 3 of 4)., 1973. (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Proposed research (Folder 4 of 4)., 1973. (Box 55, Folder 8)
      Folder includes research on violence in schools and information about proposed research at the CSRV.
    - Violence statistics (Folder 1 of 4)., 1973-1974, 1977 May 10. (Box 56, Folder 1)
      Folder contains news articles and statistics reports.
    - Violence statistics (Folder 2 of 4)., 1950-1974. (Box 56, Folder 2)
      Folder contains an interview with LJW for Practical Psychiatry on "The Violent Patient/In The Office or Clinic."
    - Violence statistics (Folder 3 of 4)., 1973-1974. (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Violence statistics (Folder 4 of 4)., 1976. (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence and research (Folder 1 of 5)., 1972 September 1-1973 August 1. (Box 56, Folder 5)
      Folder contains information about the proposed CSRV including "A Preliminary Draft on the Proposed CSRV," budget information, and memos including "Re: The Future of CSRV."
    - Correspondence and research (Folder 2 of 5)., 1973 April 12-September 10. (Box 56, Folder 6)
      Memos and information about the CSRV, including the "Report of Program & Budget: Phase One (to June 30, 1973).
    - Correspondence and research (Folder 3 of 5)., 1973 January 22-April 26. (Box 56, Folder 7)
      Folder contains correspondence and information regarding the CSRV.
    - Correspondence and research (Folder 4 of 5)., 1973-1974. (Box 56, Folder 8)
      Folder includes research, proposals, and memos related to violence and the CSRV.
    - Correspondence and research (Folder 5 of 5)., 1971, 1973 Jan 11-Jun22. (Box 56, Folder 9)
      Folder contains correspondence, memos, articles, and papers regarding the CSRV and violent behavior.
    - Correspondence and newspaper clippings (Folder 1 of 3)., 1972 September 1-1974 April 25. (Box 57, Folder 1)
      Folder contains materials related to articles published in the Daily Bruin about controversy surrounding the proposed CSRV (Center for the Prevention of Violence), particularly student protests against experimentation and racial profiling.
    - Correspondence and newspaper clippings (Folder 2 of 3)., 1972 February 4-1973 April 25. (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence and newspaper clippings (Folder 3 of 3)., 1973 April 9-July 22. (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Folder contains correspondence and articles regarding the CSRV and "The Psychosurgery Flap."
    - Correspondence, newspaper clippings, and research., 1973 January 19-September 25. (Box 57, Folder 4)
      Folder contains correspondence, memos, a public information release, and news articles regarding the SCRV. Includes a list of "Ongoing NPI research which may be transferred to center (CSRV) program."